Android Application Developer
Flutter Developer
IBRARHUSSAIN
SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Phone: (+92) 3338797067

Email: ibrar.hussain8797@gmail.com

Address: Quaid - e - Azam Marble Street Near

Al-Hussain Amabargha, Lahore

## Objective:

A forward-thinking developer offering 4 years of experience building, integrating, testing, and supporting Android applications for mobile and tablet devices on the Android platform. I learn new stuff every day to be on a top of Android technologies and best practices

Experienced with Android Studio & Eclipse. Most of my projects oriented on mobile and tablets.

- Created 15+ fully functional applications for Android devices
- Known for writing efficient, maintainable and reusable code
- Proficient in design, data structures, problem-solving, and debugging
- Expert in the interaction between various devices and versions of Android

#### **Skills**

## **Tools and Technologies:**

Android Studio, Eclipse, Adobe Photoshop, Gitlab VCS, Microsoft Office, IntelliJ, Sublime Text

#### **Android Skills:**

Retrofit, Volley, Rxjava, Coroutine, Firebase, Google maps, MVVM, Dagger2, Room Database, Live Data, SugarORM, Push Notification

## Languages:

Core Java, Kotlin, Xml, Html, CSS, C++, PHP, Dart

# Database:

SQLite, MySQL, SQL Server

#### SDLC Model:

Agile Model, Scrum Model, Jira Board, Gitlab Board, Rapid Programing

### **Achievements:**

- In-depth publishing experience of Android apps in the app store.
- Capable of trouble shooting and code enhancements.
- Experience with Android SDK
- Experience working with remote data via REST and JSON
- Experience with third-party libraries and APIs
- Working knowledge of the general mobile landscape, architectures, trends, and emerging technologies Solid understanding of the full mobile development life cycle.
- Experience with Material designing
- · Debugging for Finding Bug and optimize code

### **Work Experience**

## ANDROID DEVELOPER - Punjab Information Technology Board- Lahore - July 2020 - Present

As Android Developer, I have worked on different government projects from scratch to maintaining different already built projects.

- Experience with Java IDEs (e.g., Android Studio), profilers, debuggers, revision control systems (e.g., GIT) and bug tracking (e.g., Jira)
- Experience developing applications on Android
- Member of a team of 15 Android Engineers charged with improving the technical foundation, user experience
- App(s) published on the Play Store demonstrating a strong product focus and an eye for design
- Demonstrated interest in working with smaller startups and/or on smaller teams

- Solid understanding of mobile development lifecycle, specific technologies and submission guidelines and processes
- Previous experiences on different development fields (Backend or Java, Koltin)
- Enterprise software development experience

### ANDROID DEVELOPER - Upgenics International- Lahore - FEB 2019 - June 2020

#### **PHONECHECK**

https://www.phonecheck.com

Phone Check is complete phone solution for android, iPhone and Windows mobiles it is a product which is operated by UPGENICS INTERNATIONAL. In this project there are some tests like camera, speaker, ear speaker, NFC, Wi-Fi and more which is automatically and manually performed by user to check there phone hardware I am working on this product as Android Developer my primary focus on this product is maintaining app from bugs, adding new feature in it and optimizing code and performance.

- RESTful API integration using Retrofit2 and Rxjava
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Work with outside data sources and APIs
- Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency
- Handling various technical aspects like coding of modules using given design specifications, debugging and fixing the defects as well as analytic root cause

## ANDROID DEVELOPER - Inoviks Soft Solution- Faisalabad - SEP 2017 - FEB 2019

- Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Work with outside data sources and APIs
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.

### COMPUTER OPERATOR - Masood Textile Mills - Faisalabad - FEB 2017 - Aug 2017

- Experienced in working with Oracle Forms, Bi Publisher, Report Builder
- Scan Barcodes and enter data in management system of MTM
- Track the job timing of employee check in and out time of employee
- · Reports generation using MTM management system

# **Education**

- BS (SOFTWARE ENGINEE RING) University of Gujrat 2012-2016
  - Specialization: Android Application Development
- FSC (PRE ENGEENRING) B.I.S.E FSD 2009-2011
- MATRIC (PRE-SCIENCE) B.I.S.E FSD 2007-2009

#### Reference

Available on request